Edgar Vargas

Computer Science Graduate, Machine Operator.

West Valley City, UT 84120 edvargas1817@gmail.com 3853712867

Professional Summary

Dedicated computer science graduate, proficient in programming languages such as HTML, CSS and Java. Possess a strong understanding of computer systems and software troubleshooting. Seeking a remote or in-person computer programming role.

Also with 3 years of work experience relating to Bottle Manufacturing Industry with 1 and a half years of experience as a Machine Operator, 1 year of Material Handling, and half a year of quality inspection.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Machine Operator

Pretium Packaging-Salt Lake City, UT July 2023 to December 2024

Plastics injection mold operator.

Worked on NISSEI ASB-150DP Machines, learned most of the in's and out's such as the machinery, sensors, pneumatics, etc. And had a high understanding on processing.

Also learned about AOKI AL-250LL-50S Machines, learned the machine operator 1 basics and trained on machine operator 2 processing.

Material Handler

Pretium Packaging-Salt Lake City, UT November 2021 to July 2023

Managing, transporting and setting the correct raw material for the injection blow mold machines to operate with. Also combining, consolidating and organizing said raw materials.

Quality Inspector/Packer

Pretium Packaging-Salt Lake City, UT July 2021 to November 2021

Packing plastic bottles for final goods.

Mainly working on the end of the production line, receiving final bottles/goods and inspecting them before packing/stacking them into boxes or onto pallets to be wrapped and sent as the final product.

Also organized and prepared more of the cartons needed to be able to pack and store said final product.

Technical Customer Support Representative

CiberNetics-Michoacán January 2012 to April 2021

Family owned business, rented computer and video game console use. Daily tasks:

- 1. Helping customers solve their software device problems(such as computers, cellphones, tablets, etc.).
- 2. Assist customer with recovering email addresses and/or social network profiles.
- 3. Create an online profile for customer(PlayStation Network, Xbox Live, Nintendo account, Steam, Epic Games, etc).
- 4. Educating customers on using Microsoft Office Programs(Word, Excel, Power Point).
- 5. Making en masse copies of physical documents.

IT Trainee

Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)-Guadalajara, Jal. August 2019 to January 2020

- Internship for college.
- Learned other programming languages such as Python and JavaScript.
- Learned newer and more efficient workflows used.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Instituto Tecnológico de La Piedad - La Piedad de Cabadas, Mich.

August 2014 to December 2019

Mainly studied a lot of basics that involve technologies in different areas of tech, these being:

Computer Programming

- NetBeans IDE Java, C/C++
- Python

Databases

- MySQL
- Relational Databases

Network Architecture/ Web

Cisco Packet Tracer

Frontend Web Development

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

Backend Web Development

- PHP
- JavaScript
- Nodejs

Newer Technologies

- Raspberry Pi
- Al Technology and integrations

Skills

- Java (4 years)
- Plastics injection molding (1 year)
- Software troubleshooting (10+ years)

- HTML5 (4 years)
- MySQL (4 years)
- Packaging (2 years)
- Windows
- Materials handling (1 year)
- Computer Science (6 years)
- C/C++ (4 years)
- Plastics injection molding (Less than 1 year)
- · Microsoft Office
- Forklift (1 year)

Languages

- Spanish Fluent
- English Fluent

Certifications and Licenses

Engineering in Computer Science

March 2020 to Present

Driver's License

March 2022 to March 2030

Assessments

Filing & organization — Proficient

April 2021

Arranging and managing information or materials using a set of rules

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.